(Transcribed by TurboScribe.ai. Go Unlimited to remove this message.) All my memories from that time are generally
pretty fuzzy.
I had a lot of sensory issues.
I wouldn't touch certain things and I wouldn't
socialize.
I kept to myself, um, and I was
fixated on ceiling fans.
I would always beg my parents to take
me to Dan's fans, which was a local
fan place so that I could look at
all the ceiling fans and that alone should
have made it pretty obvious that I was
autistic because that's something only an autistic child
would do.
But I mean, what's funny is my parents
were, were trained to teach autistic kids and
they, uh, I suppose when it's right in
front of you, it can be the hardest
to see.
I believe the first time I was taken
to a psychiatrist was when I was around
three when I wouldn't socialize with the other
kids in preschool and I was diagnosed with
social anxiety disorder.
And then I kept being taken to psychiatrists
over and over again.
Like when I was seven, I was diagnosed
with, uh, ADHD.
And, um, I, around that age, I was
seeing a counselor at one point, uh, for
a little bit.
And then when I was 11, I was
diagnosed with a major depressive disorder and general
anxiety disorder.
And, uh, OCD and I mean, it always
felt like I would just never be able
to function anywhere.
Like no matter what, I would always make
myself unwelcome everywhere I went and I would
never function and I would never be able
to get along with anyone.
And I would never be able to live
any kind of, you know, functioning life, uh,
anywhere.
I felt like early warning signs that, that
I was doomed in life.
Basically I had some issues in elementary school.
Like one incident I remember was when, uh,
the teacher was having people spell words and
I spelled the word correctly and the teacher
insisted I had spelled it wrong.
And then the next person who she had
spelled it spelled it the exact same way
that I did.
And the teacher said they spelled it right.
And I threw a huge tantrum and, and
was, was crying and everything and threatened to
kill myself.
Um, that, uh, of course my, uh, my
mom was told about that and was concerned
about it.
Uh, that was things like that happened from,
from time to time.
But, uh, it only seemed to get worse
as I got older and eventually I suppose
my mother decided that I could no longer
function in an environment like that.
Yeah, it was, the internet really isn't, isn't
a place for a child to be on,
especially with unfettered and unmonitored access and really
most of the big problems I've, I've had
over the years can in some way or
another be traced back to the internet.
Because I suppose when you spend that, that
amount of time on the internet, you get
bored and, and nothing really feels real to
you and, and the real world and the
internet and everything else become blurred and become
sort of like a dreamlike state.
My mom would often say that I spent
too much time on the internet, but she
didn't really do much of anything to change
that.
Uh, there were, I mean, I remember there
were some times I was feeling particularly hateful
at the world and was trying to come
up with some new ways I could like
really piss people off on a huge scale.
But for the most part, I was just
doing things like at random.
It really seemed like something that I did
just simply for no real reason.
Other than because I could, to be perfectly
honest.
I mean, that probably isn't the answer you're
looking for, but it's the truth.
It was just basically for the hell of
it because I could.
I remember when I got kicked out of
some homeschool group, uh, I, I sent that
site to the, to the teacher.
They kicked me out and she, uh, she
called my mom and, uh, said something about,
uh, uh, a pornographic website.
It was the most vile and disgusting thing
she had ever seen.
And it gave her a Trojan virus and
she had contacted the authorities about it.
And, um, you know, my mom chalked it
up to just her being crazy, but nothing
ever happened as a result of it.
Because I highly doubt the FBI or whoever
she sent, she contacted cared very much about
an 11 year old sending her a link
to a back when I was posting on
the Sega forums, when I was 12, um,
I remember people on the board talking about
how, uh, they were sick of the, when
they shut down the Nintendo forums, they were
sick of all these kids from the Nintendo
forums coming in and shitting up the Sega
forums.
So I created this sock account, pretending to
be one of those stereotypical Nintendo kids that
I called the account.
People who had Nintendo are like mean and
just posted some stupid shit, pretending to be,
you know, an annoying Nintendo fan who was
obviously a kid.
What had initially led to me getting, getting
banned permanently from Wikipedia was when I created
a troll account called anti-Colonel Sanders and
vandalized Wikipedia news articles saying that Colonel Sanders
was responsible for the nine 11 attacks.
And it was found out that that was
me.
And then an email ended up getting sent
about it to, uh, to my mom's email
address.
Since I had used that email address to
register my Wikipedia account.
So there was a an emotional confrontation about
it with my mom.
When I was 11, I do remember watching
certain porn videos when I was 11 years
old.
Um, some of them like, uh, there were
a few, uh, like really depraved, uh, hentai
releases.
As I remember watching when I was 11.
Um, and again, it was sort of like
the same as like the, uh, the gore
stuff, you know, it was like, wow, this,
this stuff exists, you know, um, people, people
can be so depraved.
Um, and you know, again, that's not really
something that any child with a developing brain
should receive heavy exposure to.
Like, I remember as a kid saying, I
wanted to make a movie about the war
in Iraq.
And, you know, another time saying I wanted
to make a biopic about Hitler, um, which
are not things that, you know, a typical
kid would, would talk about making movies of,
but, um, I, I, uh, I was very
familiar with, you know, with mature films.
And so I, uh, I wanted to, um,
you know, be a very versatile filmmaker, I
suppose.
I often made a lot of discussion threads
about very mature subjects when I was 11
that you would never think an 11 year
old kid had been behind those threads.
I'm actually very thankful that, that, um, the
posts that I made from when I was
that age on IMDB are no longer in
existence because they were the most cringe inducing
posts I made on any site.
My behavior was so obnoxious and so just
off putting at the time, especially on sites
like that.
And looking back on it, it's just, like
when I look at the 14 year old
me, I do see like, you know, a
lot of echoes of the infamous internet, lolcows
like Christian Weston Chandler, you know, the ones
that I said I never wanted to be
like, but to some extent I was like
that when I was 14 at least.
And there was a picture that had been
taken of, of me with, with a, uh,
with a, with a llama at some petting
zoo or something.
And, um, I, I tried to scan it
in just to show it to a few
people.
And, um, at one point I, I posted
it on in a comment on someone's Facebook
page.
That was from IMDB.
And I, I, I mean, at the time
I knew that, that it could get out.
So I don't know why I posted it
anyways, but then someone messaged me with, with
a copy of it.
So I made this big dramatic thread about
it on IMDB and then people started, uh,
well, yeah, there was, it was, all the
reactions were just making fun of it and,
and making edits of it.
Crude, crude edits, like, you know, putting dicks
in Photoshopped in my mouth and things like
that, which actually I'm pretty sure is, is
a crime considering that I was 14 at
the time.
The guy who, who had made those meme
edits of my picture, I, I posted his,
his, his number in, uh, you know, in
retaliation.
Um, like I would look at certain violent
content on purpose, like, uh, that I had,
I had read about or whatever.
Um, like, like I, I've said before, that
was back when, uh, you know, shock sites
were a big thing on the internet.
Uh, I remember looking at, uh, snuff X
and reading like some of the stuff that
like, for example, um, some guy was begging
the webmaster to take down, uh, some pictures
or videos of, uh, his girlfriend who had
been, I guess, brutally dismembered.
And the webmaster loudly refusing to in a
really nasty way.
And I remember reading that and thinking, wow,
this stuff is just evil.
Like these people are evil.
Um, and the, the, you know, seeing a
lot of that stuff sort of showed me
a firsthand the, the kind of, I mean,
it gave you a sort of a taste
of the kind of evil that exists in
the world.
Seeing people be so horrible on the internet
sort of turned me into, into someone who,
who viewed humanity as a whole as, as
being horrible.
And it, I suppose grew into like me
trying to, you know, I, I suppose on
a lot of levels, I wanted other people
to, to have that same miserable worldview as
me.
So I would go out of my way
to, to be as horrible as possible, just
to show people how horrible people are, which
sounds absolutely ridiculous.
But, uh, I suppose that was sort of
my, my mindset.
A lot of the times when I was
around that age.
Well, it's a, it's a sad reality of,
of human nature, that no matter what it
is, people will always find some way to
use it for evil purposes.
If there's one thing in the world that
has absolutely no limits whatsoever, it is the
cruelty and depravity of human beings.
I remember having a, a, a sort of
obsession with this, this guy on, on IMDb
who went by the username YSH227, and he
would post these incredibly long detailed stories about
how he was supposedly kidnapping, raping, torturing, killing,
and eating little girls.
And I mean, he also included these very
realistic looking photographs to go with them.
And, uh, looking back now, I'm, I'm sure
that it was all complete bullshit, but it,
it looked so genuine, especially when I was
11.
And, um, I think, you know, even, even
if it was bullshit, there has to be
something seriously wrong with you for you to
even write something like that.
Um, and there was definitely something seriously wrong
with, with this guy, even if he was
just a troll.
Um, but I, I became sort of sort
of fixated on him and, and I tried
to get people to report him to the
authorities cause I believed that he was, he
was a real serial killer.
Um, and I, I posted about him so
much that that people suspected that I was
him, which very much, uh, made me angry
at the time.
There was another person, uh, who I had
talked to on IMDb and then on YouTube
for a while, who I had, he had
asked me for personal information and I had
given it to him.
And then, then later I, I became so
anxious that he did, uh, I had given
this guy personal information and I became, you
know, so worried that he was some, you
know, stalker predator who was going to hunt
me down and rape me and kill me
or something like that.
And I, I, I don't know about, I
mean, I'm sure that the story still exists
today, but, but back in the early aughts,
especially it was constant stories of scaremongering about,
about people preying on kids online and how,
if you give anyone your personal information online,
they'll they'll use that to come hunt you
down.
And so I kept ruminating on how I
had given this guy personal information of mine,
who was this guy who was acting like
he was my friend on IMDb.
And I was, I was so worried that
he was going to come hunt me down.
And I gave so much thought to that,
that it's downright ridiculous.
Uh, when people are completely anonymous and they
know that they will not be held accountable
for anything that they do or say that
brings out the absolute worst in people.
And you can see that on the internet.
You can see it in real life in
situations where people know that they will not
be held accountable for anything they do, such
as Russian soldiers or UN diplomats, for example.
Uh, that's just the worst aspects of human
nature coming out in full force.
And the internet really encourages that.
Like I would, I would take every ideological
side possible under different aliases and just post
content from each ideological side on, on their
aligned subreddits.
And, uh, you know, I started to sort
of flesh out a lot of the characters
that were, were posting these things.
Um, with the amount that I had been
exposed to actual extremists and, and, and trolls
and so forth on the internet, it was
pretty easy for me to, to imitate their,
their rhetoric and to, you know, um, to
come up with the sorts of things that
they would say.
So it was, it was not difficult for
me to do so.
Um, I remember getting a letter from a
journalist, Jacob Seigel, who expressed a sort of
admiration at my ability to, to easily imitate
the tone of so many different kinds of
people.
But it really, I suppose it wasn't, it
wasn't difficult.
And I mean, if you look, look hard
at, at the writing of, of Michael Slay,
it's, I mean, you don't even have to
look very hard.
It's pretty obvious that this is the work
of a disingenuous troll and not a sincere
neo-Nazi.
I would constantly like act like a, just
a clown.
Um, I would like, uh, I remember in
the hallways randomly, I would, I would yell,
fight the power as if that was just
hilarious.
And I would like singing class and things
like that.
And I got sent to the principal's office
pretty much every day.
And again, I don't, I don't know why
I acted like that.
I mean, I remember doing some stupid things
like that when I was a kid, like
just going around the neighborhood with a candle
lighter and setting random small fires when I
was a kid.
Um, which is going to make me sound
like a serial killer.
But, um, I remember constantly fantasizing about creating
some kind of super virus in a lab
and then using it to wipe out the
entire human race, which again is going to
make me sound like a complete psychopath.
I had, uh, sniffed gasoline a few times
when I was a kid.
Um, but when, when that happened, I, I
hadn't done that.
It was like, just my mom, uh, was
worried about my behavior and made an unbelievably
stupid decision to, to call the police saying,
hi, I have a son, uh, who is
severely depressed.
Uh, he is abusing inhalers.
Uh, something like some probably, I think she
said something about me trying to commit suicide
or something, which didn't happen.
And, uh, then they came and, uh, they
handcuffed me, but they didn't take me anywhere.
They just told my parents that they needed
to take me to a psych evaluation or
something.
And then they left.
It was probably the dumbest thing my mom
ever did.
I don't know what she hoped would be
the, the intended outcome of calling the police
on me, but it was just unbelievably stupid.
I remember one time banging my head repeatedly
against the floor when I was a kid.
I think I was like 14 or so.
And I remember around the same age, one
time, uh, cutting my wrist with a, or
my arm with a knife and then posting
about it on my yearbook, which was a
website that's now known as meet me.
My mom was exasperated with, uh, with the
constant, you know, mental issues I had.
And she, she in exhaustion told me, well,
after I said something, she was like, well,
just end it all then.
And then that night, she, the next morning
that, that, after she said that I, uh,
I had made a Facebook post about how
my mom was a bitch who told me
to kill myself.
And, um, she, the next morning apologized to
me for it for it said it was
completely inappropriate for her to say that.
But then later after that, uh, my uncle
who was my mom's brother, uh, decided to
call my mom and tell me about, uh,
the Facebook post that I had made a
while ago about it.
And that led to another conflict.
But there were a lot of conflicts like
that with, with my parents over the years.
I like to have a mysterious, enigmatic aura
about me.
You know, I like to have people wondering
And so when you're spending 24 seven online,
nothing really feels real to you anyways.
And, uh, you get sort of sucked down
these rabbit holes where you can just retreat
into, into these different characters and, and pretending
to be all these different people, which I
suppose is, is in a lot of ways,
a lot easier than, than taking on the
responsibilities of real life, because the people you're
pretending to be online are just characters.
They don't, they don't have the same responsibilities.
They don't have to worry about, uh, you
know, what kind of job they're going to
get, how they're going to live independently.
The, these characters can be whatever you want
them to be.
And, uh, no strings attached, you know, for
a lot of people when they create, you
know, just one persona on Second Life or
wherever, it's just a manifestation of who they
wish they were.
It's a fantasy for them.
And for me, that's not really what it
is.
I'm not, I'm not fantasizing about who I
wish I was.
I'm just pretending to be a million different
people all at once and coming up with,
with new characters and taking on roles because,
you know, I can, because again, on the
internet, nobody knows who you are.
Nobody knows who they're dealing with.
And they'll just most of the time, except
at face value when you say who you
are, even if it's completely false, nobody's going
to know that.
So I can be, you know, the, the,
the, I'm sure you've heard the song Bittersweet
Symphony by The Verve, where he says I'm
a million different people from one day to
the next.
And that's, that's only on the internet.
Is that really possible?
The, some of them were largely just variations
on the same character, but even so they
still had key differences.
And that level of subtlety is something that
most people don't really put into people that
run a lot of internet sock accounts.
There are, there are of course other people
that do what I was doing, where they
have all these different personas.
But even then a lot of the times
you won't find the level of subtlety and
nuance that I put into them.
And it wasn't even so much as an
effort as it was just something that I
suppose felt came naturally just to take on
these characters and give them these dimensions.
You know, I would always be, you know,
the hero and the villain at the same
time under different sort of masks, I suppose
you could say.
Even a lot of the personas were not
just trolling.
I mean like some of them were just,
just creating characters, you know, like the, I
showed you the one, the Micronesia gal account
that you would ask me what the purpose
behind that was.
You said you thought it was clever.
Just someone claiming to be a school teacher
in Micronesia trying to help her students lose
weight.
Just, you know, created characters.
I'm this, this 14 year old half Jewish
kid sitting at a computer, but I can
have these people actually think that I'm some
big, bad neo-Nazi skinhead.
And it's just, it's crazy to have that
kind of power over people, even if it's
just a small power, you know, even if
it's not really anything meaningful.
It's just crazy to think that people will
just believe that you are that person even
when you couldn't possibly be farther from it.
I would pretend to be these people on
complete opposite ends of the ideological spectrum along
with everything in between and would often set
them up to fight each other, you know,
and, um, a lot of the times when,
uh, when I was acting as a neo
-Nazi, I was like, basically most of it
was, was trolling, you know, trying to, to
make people angry and, and trying to make,
you know, the neo-Nazis look like idiots,
which they are, which I'd say I succeeded
in doing.
You know, I, I often, I tried to
like, I often tried to see like how,
how extreme I could possibly make the rhetoric
before even the neo-Nazis would start to
object, you know, like, like, do they have
any limits?
You know, how extreme can I get before
any of them will say anything?
But every single time they would all just
eat up everything I said that they're, when
they're talking amongst themselves, there are no limits
to what they say.
Um, and it's the same way with a
lot of the ideological extremists on every end
of the political spectrum.
You know, when they're talking amongst themselves, they're
openly talking about, you know, straight up killing
people.
And they don't have any hesitations about it.
And you learn that really quickly when you're
infiltrating these people online.
When I published, for example, the thing on
the times of Israel that actually made the
news all over the world.
And so did when I, when I trolled
Twitter ads and, and things like that, I
was actually, actually making a significant impact.
And it felt like I actually had some
kind of power, you know, otherwise in my
life, I felt completely powerless.
I felt like my life didn't have any
meaning, but when I'm, you know, stirring up
conflicts on the internet, I'm, I'm, I'm actually
having power over people without actually having to
even barely lift a finger.
All I have to do is type some
words on a screen.
And I'm making the news all over the
world.
And, and I'm, I'm, I'm, people are having
so strong reactions to, to what I'm doing
and saying.
And it, it felt like, like, finally, I,
I have some degree of power.
You know, I've always been the most powerless
person around.
I've, I've always been, you know, looked down
on by everyone, but on the internet, I,
I could, uh, you know, I, I, I
had some degree of control, I suppose.
I suppose I started spending more, more of
that online time on these, you know, uh,
trolling operations and on these personas, because I
was actually, I was actually, I mean, it
sounds pathetic when I say it, but I
was getting somewhere with them.
Uh, and it was, you know, the, the
first time I had actually had any kind
of success with anything to be perfectly honest.
I had gotten one of Tanya Cohen's hoax
articles published in an Australian publication.
But as far as, uh, me writing as
Joshua Goldberg, I had been pretty much rejected
across the board.
It's hard to say, but I suppose I
felt like I could potentially have some kind
of employment on the internet, you know, writing
things.
And, and, uh, that was one of the
reasons I was infiltrating the jihadists.
Cause I thought that that could potentially be
a path to employment.
And I was, I was trying to get
some, get something of mine published in, in
a, you know, a reputed publication.
I remember him posting one of my old
thought catalog articles, and then I contacted him,
uh, through email with, uh, the, the story
about Shaun King and, uh, he liked it
and, and published it.